Nelma Perera

http://npererar.me

Email: npererar@gmail.com | GitHub: github.com/nelmiux | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/npererar

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Innovative **web** and **mobile** developer, with years of experience in **object-oriented** programming; **developing**, **testing** and **debugging** code. Highly self-motivated learner, who quickly **adapt** and master **new technologies**. Successful working in both **team** and **individual** environments.

EDUCATION

B.S. in Computer Science, University of Texas at Austin

May, 2016

EXPERIENCE

iOS Developer / todo mobile app, University of Texas at Austin https://github.com/iOS-Mobile-Dev/todo

January, 2016 – May, 2016

One of three developers on the team that built a P2P on-demand tutoring service for iOS app. Enabling an
immediate, easy and affordable way for students to get a private assistance on their subject of difficulty, while
paying the tutor time and effort with an alternative electronic currency system.

Technologies: Swift, Objective-C, Cocoa Touch, Xcode, Firebase, RESTful, JSON.

Android Developer / Photoball mobile app, University of Texas at Austin https://github.com/Android-Mobile-Dev/Photoball

January, 2016 – May, 2016

• One of three developers on the team that built an Android game app. It allows to take images from a device's camera or gallery and generate an edges map based on that, afterwards a user's controlled ball can interact and bounce over the edges from the generated environment.

Technologies: Java, XML, Android Studio, Android SDK.

Research Assistant, University of Texas at Austin

January, 2016 - May, 2016

https://github.com/nelmiux/CarnotKE

 Researcher and developer of a platform that allows automatic translation of SQL-to SPARQL over a Jena JDBC adapter.

Technologies: Java, Python, Jena JDBC Driver, IntelliJ, Oracle Database, RDF, SPARQL.

Back-End Web Developer / GotoPaws web app, University of Texas at Austin June, 2015 – August, 2015 <u>https://github.com/nsaid-team/gotopaws</u>

• One of five developers on the team that built a web app that's provides a single centralized environment for animal's lovers to find information about shelters, parks, vets, groomers, and pets up for adoption.

Technologies: Python, Django, UML, MVC, MySQL, RESTful API, Apiary, ElasticSearch, JSON, Bootstrap, HTML/XML, JavaScript, JQuery.

CEO, Software Developer, IT Consultant / Binarium Technology, Florida

2008 - 2012

• Responsible for all day-to-day management decisions, and everything else. Sometimes team leader and sometimes team member of a multiples web, mobile and few desktop development projects.

Technologies: C++, C#, ASP.NET, Java, Python, iOS, Android, PHP, HTML, JavaScript, MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server, JQuery, Visual Studio, Linux.

SKILLS / TECHNOLOGIES SUMMARY

Java, Python, Swift, Objective-C, C++, C#, PHP, HTML, JavaScript, UML, Oracle SQL, Microsoft SQL Server, MySQL, SPARQL, NEO4J, ASP.NET, MVC, Cocoa Touch, Android SDK, Django, Bootstrap, JQuery, Firebase, ElasticSearch.